<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<article xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
         xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
         dtd-version="1.0"
         article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id journal-id-type="jstor">amereconrevi</journal-id>
         <journal-id journal-id-type="jstor">j100009</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>The American Economic Review</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>The American Economic Association</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn pub-type="ppub">00028282</issn>
         <custom-meta-group/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">1803623</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>The Effect of Modern Technological Conditions upon the Employment of Labor</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Edna</given-names>
                  <surname>Lonigan</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date>
            <day>1</day>
            <month>6</month>
            <year>1939</year>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">29</volume>
         <issue xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">2</issue>
         <issue-id>i331289</issue-id>
         <fpage>246</fpage>
         <lpage>259</lpage>
         <page-range>246-259</page-range>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright 1939 The American Economic Association</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/1803623"/>
         <abstract>
            <p>This paper was delivered before a Round Table on Wages and Hours in Relation to Innovations and Capital Formation at the Fifty-first Annual Meeting of the American Economic Association in Detroit, Michigan, December 30, 1938. Explanations of falling general employment must be found elsewhere than in displacement of workers by machines. Chief incentives to labor saving in two business cycles from 1914 to 1933 were the rise of management to power in industry and the high cost of protective programs for labor. Falling costs of production should have led to increased employment in consumers' goods, recreation and services. Failure of such compensating employments to appear in the 1920's is due to the post-war fallacy of the stable price level, to absence of credit facilities for enterprise and to inflexibility of fixed charges for corporation salaries, accounting abstractions and debts. Since 1933 the rate of change has greatly increased and compensating adjustments in prices, investment and obsolete debt must be even more rapid and extensive than for the 1920's. The chief need is to find reintegrating forces equal to the disintegrating forces in economic society and so provide full employment that maintains itself out of its own earned income.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
</article>
